[Kurapika]
This country's open to tourists.
That's where Killua is?
It'll take three days to reach by airship.
When do you think we should leave?
-Today! Right now!
-Alright! I'm with Gon.
Got it. I'll order the tickets then.
[theme music playing]
[Killua]
I'm from a family of assassins, so yeah,
they're all in the business of murder.
And my entire family,
they've got real high hopes for me.
But y'know, I can't stand it.
Who wants their whole life mapped out
for them?
Killua...
So, what's the deal
with the long face, Gon?
By tomorrow, we'll be in Padokea.
You'll see Killua soon.
Yup!
[Gon] We'll definitely bring Killua
back with us!
A x DANGEROUS x WATCHDOG
[narrator] Gon, Leorio, and Kurapika
have arrived in the Dentora region
of the Republic of Padokea,
which Killua calls home.
[Leorio] I can almost see it.
So that's where the assassins' base is?
-It looks kind of creepy, doesn't it?
-[Kurapika] It does.
Once we arrive,
we should gather information.
[Leorio] Okay.
[Shopkeeper] Kukuroo Mountain...
You'll want to take
the scenic mountain bus tour over there.
It only runs once a day, but you'll have
a guide to show you around.
[tour guide] I'd like to thank all of you
for choosing Lamentation Tours.
It's an honor to have you here.
Now, get ready, because we'll be making
our way up to Kukuroo Mountain,
home to the Zoldyck family of assassins.
Check it out.
No way those guys are tourists.
-True.
-[tour guide] Okay, everyone!
If you'll all look out the window
to your right...
[Gon gasps]
...you'll see Kukuroo Mountain
where the Zoldyck family lives.
It's 3,722-meter high,
and it's surrounded by forest.
The Zoldyck estate is rumored to be
somewhere on the mountain.
although no one has ever actually seen it.
The Zoldyck family consists
of ten members:
Mother and Father, five siblings,
grandparents and great-grandfather,
all of whom are assassins!
Alright, now hold on, while we get
a little closer to the mountain.
Would you look at that...
This is the front gate
of the Zoldyck estate.
No one who's entered
has ever returned alive,
which has earned this gate the nickname
"the Door to Hades."
To enter, you have to go through the door
by the security checkpoint.
But beyond that is private property,
so this is as far as we can go.
[Leorio] Hold on! This is the front gate?
The mountain is all the way over there!
That's right. The Zoldyck family
own Kukuroo Mountain, every inch of it,
not to mention all the surrounding land.
So, what you're telling me
is this is their front yard?
-Miss Tour Guide?
-Yes?
What are we gonna have to do
to get inside?
Hmm. Oh, dear.
You were paying attention, right?
Yeah, but you didn't say--
If you go inside,
you'll never come out again!
It's an assassins' hideout.
-It's a sham.
-Huh?
A family of assassins
no one's ever seen?
If we can just snap a picture of them,
we're gonna get a hundred million
in reward money.
Are you kidding me? Damn it!
I should have taken a picture of Killua!
[both groan]
They probably rely on the mystique
to protect them.
I bet the truth is a whole lot
less interesting.
Huh?
[yells]
-Open up the gate!
-I'm afraid I can't.
The master of the house would not approve
of such a thing.
Don't worry about that.
We kinda figured
we'd kill your master anyway.
[sighs]
[guard grunts]
-[moans]
-Are you okay?
-Yes, I'll be alright.
-[gate creaking open]
Oh, darn! The master hates it
when Mike snacks between meals.
-What?
-[men yelling]
[all gasp]
[all yelp]
[screams]
[everyone clamoring]
[guard] Well, damn it.
Mike's only supposed to eat
at designated times.
Mike!
Don't blame those extra pounds on me!
What was that thing?
Hey, you guys! What are you doing?
Time to get back on the bus!
Go ahead without us
'cause we're all staying here.
What?
[guard] I see.
So, you're young Master Killua's friends,
are you?
Happy to hear it.
I've worked here for the past 20 years,
and to the best of my recollection,
you three are the first friends
who've ever come to visit.
Now, I probably shouldn't be telling you
this, seeing as how I work here,
but this place is pretty lonely.
No one ever really visits.
Well, except those types.
We get our fair share of those. [chuckles]
But a family of assassins
is bound to be unusual.
I guess that's the price
they have to pay.
Oh, well. Anyways,
I'm so glad you're here.
-Thank you for coming.
-Don't mention it.
However...
That doesn't mean I'm going to be able
to let any of you inside.
You saw it earlier, didn't you?
How huge the beast's arm was?
That arm belongs to Mike.
It's the Zoldycks' watchdog.
It only obeys the family
and attacks everyone else.
As a matter of fact, it's still following
the order its master gave ten years ago...
To kill every single intruder
who tries to get inside.
I guess he isn't following it technically
because he keeps eating them.
[laughs]
But, like I was saying,
I can't let you in.
I wouldn't want friends
of young Master Killua
being stripped down to their skeletons.
[laughs]
Question. How is it that you're safe here?
-Hmm?
-It's just, you can go inside.
and if you were never allowed to go in,
it's unlikely
that you would be given a key.
Hmm, that's very perceptive,
but the fact is,
you're only about half right.
See, I don't need a key to get inside.
This key was specially made
for intruders only.
There's a key for intruders?
Almost all of them
go right for the front gate.
About 90 percent.
I couldn't begin to tell you why, though.
If I don't open the gate for them,
every time without fail,
they try to break it down.
They're real troublemakers, these types.
That's why we added a locked door
to one side. It works pretty well.
They just take the key from the poor,
helpless security guard,
and then Mike eats them.
It's as simple as that.
[Kurapika] A locked door?
That's it!
As you just realized,
I'm not a security guard.
I'm just the janitor
who cleans up after Mike,
So, the front gate isn't actually locked
after all.
-Exactly.
-What?
HUNTER GLOSSARY
LAMENTATION TOUR
I've pushed and pulled
but it won't budge!
Are you sure the gate isn't locked?
[guard]
I'm afraid you're just not strong enough.
Shut up! I was giving it
everything I've got!
Step back and watch.
This gate is officially known
as the Testing Gate,
because anyone who's not strong enough
to open it...
-[grunts]
-[gust of wind blows]
...is considered unworthy of entering
the Zoldyck estate.
[grunts]
[all gasp]
[door thuds shut]
So, you can see that the door
closes automatically,
so you'll want to slip inside
as soon as it opens.
And you won't need to worry about Mike.
He has strict orders not to attack anyone
who enters through the Testing Gate.
Whew. The older I get,
the tougher this seems to become.
But they'll fire me
if I can't open the gate,
so, I need to stay fit.
And I should mention,
the first doors weigh two tons each.
What? You're really not supposed
to be able to...
Wait, what did you say?
-Did you say the first doors?
-Yeah, take a look.
There are seven doors in all.
And keep in mind that each set is twice
as heavy as the set of doors before it.
[Leorio] Twice?
The more force you put into it,
the more doors you open.
Gotta be pretty strong
to get through all of them.
Incidentally, when young Master Killua
returned to the estate,
he opened three of them, just like that.
Three? That's like...12 tons!
-It's 16 tons, Gon.
-[laughs]
[guard] Starting to get it now?
This is what it takes
just to get through the door.
They live in a completely different world.
[Gon] I don't like that.
May I borrow the key?
I didn't come all this way to be tested.
I came so I could see my friend.
Think of me as an intruder.
So please, let me borrow the key.
and I'll go in there
through the intruder's door.
-Gon!
-Hey.
Lend it to me, or don't,
but I'm getting in.
I'll climb the wall if I have to.
[Leorio] Don't be stupid, Gon!
Didn't you see that terrifying monster?
Its forearm was bigger than
your whole body times two!
I told you, I don't like this!
Why test your friends? It's crazy!
There's no way
I'm ever going through that door.
You're right, but if you think
you can force your way in, think again.
It's absolutely impossible.
Mike will definitely kill you.
I have to agree with you.
We have the time,
so let's find a way to use the first door.
No use.
He won't change his mind
when he's like this.
Yes, you're right.
[sighs] I'm sorry to say this,
but I can't let you have the key.
I won't feed young Master Killua's friends
to Mike. I can't do it.
Guess I don't have it in me.
But would you wait here
for a minute, please?
[dial tone]
[guard] Hello, this is Zebro.
Sorry to call. It's just that three
of young Master Killua's friends are here
and they would very much like to see him.
Yes. Yes, I'm sorry. Of course.
Yes, I understand. Yes. Yes.
I'm so very sorry to disturb you.
-Yeah, I figured I would get yelled at.
-You called up to the house for us?
No, I was speaking
with the Zoldyck family's butler.
All communication with the mansion
has to go through the butler first.
It's not easy
to reach the family members directly.
Could you get him on the phone again?
I'd like to talk to him this time.
Well, I suppose I can, but I guarantee
that you're not going to enjoy it.
[pressing buttons]
[butler]
You've reached the butler's quarters.
My name is Gon, and I'm one
of Killua's friends that came to visit.
Is Killua there? Can I speak to him?
Master Killua does not have friends.
[puts down phone]
[dial tone]
[butler]
You've reached the butler's quarters.
How could you possibly know that, huh?
Put Killua on the phone!
-I believe you said your name is Gon?
-[Gon] Yeah.
[butler] Let us pretend that Master Killua
does have a friend named Gon.
There is no proof that you are him.
Put him on the phone, he'll recognize me!
[butler] By your voice?
That is no guarantee.
[Gon] Put him on the phone,
he'll recognize me!
[butler] That was a simple recording.
but there are many other ways
to mimic someone's voice.
Next, you'll say
that he'd recognize you by sight.
There aren't as many methods
by which you could perfectly replicate
someone's appearance,
but it isn't impossible.
Or perhaps you are Gon,
but someone has coerced you
to approach Master Killua
for some sinister motive.
As long as that threat exists,
I cannot let you meet with him.
The Zoldyck family
are in the assassination business.
They have their enemies, of course.
And it is a butler's responsibility
to guard them from those enemies.
Apologies, you will have to leave.
Hey! Wait!
Gon!
He's really pissed, isn't he?
I think he's going to climb over the wall.
He what?
[Leorio] Hey, Gon! Knock it off!
It's okay. You two can wait here.
-I'm going in alone.
-I can't let you do that!
-[Gon] I'll be fine!
-[Leorio] No, you won't!
[Kurapika]
Look, both of you need to calm down!
[Leorio] I'm perfectly calm!
Now, come on, get down!
[Kurapika] He's right. Don't be stupid.
Here, Gon, I'll give you the key.
You can go through the door, alright?
Just wait a second, Pops!
We can convince him to stop this.
Oh, really? Because he strikes me
as the stubborn type.
To make amends, I've decided
to accompany you through the door.
What?
Mike knows me well enough
to recognize me.
and it's possible he might not attack
if he sees I'm with you.
Though I'm almost 100 percent certain
that he'll just kill us all.
I can't let you do that.
I don't want to cause any trouble for you.
Too late. I'm coming.
There'd be trouble even if I stayed.
If I send young Master Killua's friends
to their deaths,
I'd never be able
to look him in the eye again.
If you die, well,
then I'll die alongside you.
I understand, sir.
I guess I didn't stop
to think about your situation.
Sorry.
[guard] He's a good kid.
ready and willing to put aside
his own anger for the sake of another.
He believes in his own strength.
and he believes in his friends
just as much.
He has such a strong heart.
In fact, it's likely that
Mike won't frighten him at all.
You like animals, don't you, Gon?
Huh? Yes.
I thought you might.
And did you grow up
playing in the countryside?
Yes! How did you know all that?
Alright, in just a moment, I'm going
to open the Testing Gate again.
I want you to see Mike with your own eyes.
Hey, are you sure that it's okay
for us to come in?
Of course. You entered through
the Testing Gate, so you'll be fine.
Mike! Come here!
[Mike growling in distance]
[Gon gasps]
[guard] So, Gon, do you understand?
This is a hunting beast,
and a highly trained one at that!
It's like no animal
you've ever encountered in the wild
No, not by a long shot.
You believed you could
communicate with him
until you looked in his eyes, right?
As we speak,
Mike is memorizing the appearances
and scents of these new humans.
There isn't anything else on his mind
at the moment.
He's just like a machine.
So, Gon, do you think you could fight him?
I'd be too scared.
I don't ever want to fight him!
[guard chuckles]
He's an honest lad, too.
Well, how long will you be staying here?
Until we see Killua!
We're not leaving a second before!
[chuckles]
Alright then, follow me.
[narrator]
First, The Testing Gate, and now Mike.
Between the two of them,
Gon has seen for himself
that the Zoldyck family truly live
in a completely different world.
However, Gon had made a promise
to himself
that no matter what difficulties lay
on the path ahead of him
in the end, he would see Killua.
[theme music plays]
[Gon] Next time, "The Guard's Duty."
Five times five is 25.
[Kurapika] So, you know how to do math?
[Kurapika, Gon and Leorio]
Five times five is 25!